Don't fear the end of the world. Fear what happens next.
Pandorum is a action, horror, mystery film directed by Christian Alvart.
Two crew members wake up on an abandoned spacecraft with no idea who they
are, how long they've been asleep, or what their mission is.
The two soon discover they're actually not alone – and the reality of their
situation is more horrifying than they could have imagined.
Bower, played by Ben Foster.
Payton, played by Dennis Quaid.
Gallo, played by Cam Gigandet.
Nadia, played by Antje Traue.
Manh, played by Cung Le.
Leland, played by Eddie Rouse.
Pandorum is a 2009 science fiction horror film directed by Christian
Alvart, produced by Robert Kulzer, Jeremy Bolt and Paul W.
Anderson (the latter two through their Impact Pictures
banner), and starring Dennis Quaid and Ben Foster.
Travis Milloy wrote the screenplay from a story by Milloy and Alvart.
The film's title is a fictional slang term for a form of psychosis caused by deep space and
triggered by emotional stress, leading to severe paranoia, delirium, and nosebleeds.
Pandorum was released on 25 September 2009 in the United
States, and on 2 October 2009 in the UK.
The film was poorly received and a box office flop.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, mission, mutation, dystopia, survival.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.